<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Splat | Derik Strattan's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://Derikulous.github.io/blog/categories/splat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Derikulous.github.io/"/>
<<<<<<< HEAD:blog/categories/splat/atom.xml


  <updated>2013-12-27T22:18:55-08:00</updated>


=======
  <updated>2014-01-03T16:45:30-08:00</updated>
>>>>>>> source:public/blog/categories/splat/atom.xml
  <id>http://Derikulous.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derik Strattan]]></name>

  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>


  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blackjack? A Rubeque splat problem.]]></title>
    <link href="http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/12/27/blackjack-how-to-use-splat/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-27T16:35:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/12/27/blackjack-how-to-use-splat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://img62.imageshack.us/img62/2504/midgarmeteor.jpg">http://img62.imageshack.us/img62/2504/midgarmeteor.jpg</a>" title="&ldquo;Final Fantasy VII Meteor&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>In my previous <a href="https://derikulous.github.io/year/12/25/splicing-arrays/">post</a>, I explained in detail how Ruby handles splicing of an array, specifically index vs. position. I&rsquo;ve been working through Rubeque problems, and came up against a splat operator problem <b><a href="http://www.rubeque.com/problems/blackjack/solutions">here</a></b>. I had seen the splat operator a few times in Rails, but didn&rsquo;t have a solid grasp on its functionality.</p>

<p>Before exploring the inner workings of the splat operator, and ultimately how to solve the Rubeque problem, let&rsquo;s review how we can add multiple arguments into a method:</p>

<p>``` ruby
def sum(num_one, num_two, num_three)
  num_one + num_two + num_three
end</p>

<p>puts sum(1, 2, 5) # => 8
```
The above example illustrates how to define a set of parameters for one method by separating each parameter with a comma. This code is easy to read, however it isn&rsquo;t DRY. Think about if you had a class and had to define multiple methods like this, each with multiple parameters. You can see how the above solution would get quickly obfuscated.</p>

<p>So, to DRY up the code, we can use the splat operator. <b>What is a splat operator?</b>
This fancy Ruby (also available in Python) operator defines a variable number of arguments (read: an unknown number of argument). It is defined with an asterisk, like so: <code>*args</code>. Using the first example, we could redefine the solution as such:</p>

<p>``` ruby
def sum *num
  num.inject(0) { |sum, num| sum + num }
end</p>

<p>puts sum(1, 2, 5)
```</p>

<p>Going through this step by step: <br>
1) Define the sum method <code>def sum</code>. <br>
2) Use the splat operator <code>*num</code> to define an argument <strong>num</strong>. <br>
3) Whoa, what is inject? Don&rsquo;t panic&hellip; inject simply combines all elements by applying a binary operation, specified by the block <code>||</code>. .inject can be passed in an initial value, hence the <code>num.inject(0)</code>. If we used <code>num.inject(21)</code>, then we would begin summing values starting at 21. <br>
4) Define the block. According to the <a href="http://www.ruby-doc.org/core-1.9.3/Enumerable.html#method-i-inject">Ruby docs</a>, the block takes in an accumulator <em>value</em> and an element.<br></p>

<p>What does all of this mean? In plain English, it looks like this:<br>
<code>ruby
sum begins at 0
sum is defined as an array [1, 2, 5]
the first value in the array is passed to num, in this case value equals 1
sum + num =&gt; 0 + 1 =&gt; 1
sum now equals 1
the second value (2) in the array is passed to num
sum + num =&gt; 1 + 2 =&gt; 3
sum now equals 3
the last value (5) in the array is passed to num
sum + num =&gt; 3 + 5 =&gt; 8
sum now equals 8
</code></p>

<p>The Rubeque instructions are as follows: <strong>Write a method that takes any number of integers and returns true if they sum to 21, false otherwise. Hint: splat operator.</strong></p>

<p>The final code that we want to match is
<code>ruby
assert_equal twenty_one?(3, 4, 5, 6, 3), true
</code></p>

<p>Since we know how to use the splat operator now, we can solve the problem:
<code>ruby
def twenty_one? *num
  num.inject { |sum, num| sum + num } == 21
end
</code></p>

<p>We did not need to explicitly define the beginning value in this case. Since Ruby 1.9+, the code can be further DRYed:<br>
<code>ruby
def twenty_one? *num
  num.inject(:+) == 21
end
</code>
I hope you enjoyed reading this post on splat operators. I learned a great deal by writing it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>

</feed>
