<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: troubleshooting | Derik Strattan's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://Derikulous.github.io/blog/categories/troubleshooting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Derikulous.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-27T22:24:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://Derikulous.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derik Strattan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to display FontAwesome in Firefox using Rails and CloudFront]]></title>
    <link href="http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/11/16/how-to-fontawesome/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-16T16:33:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/11/16/how-to-fontawesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://25.media.tumblr.com/8f8d4d311eeca74a0496233c087dbbae/tumblr_mw6av9Opmb1rbnw5do2_500.gif">http://25.media.tumblr.com/8f8d4d311eeca74a0496233c087dbbae/tumblr_mw6av9Opmb1rbnw5do2_500.gif</a>" title="&ldquo;5 cm per second&rdquo;" ></p>

<h3> Winter is almost upon us; the perfect time for staying indoors and coding!</h3>


<h1>Topics covered:</h1>

<ol>
  <li>Cloudfront configuration</li>
  <li>Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) gem</li>
</ol>


<h1>What are we learning?</h1>

<p>
  In my <a href="https://derikulous.github.io/year/11/03/installing-twitter-bootstrap/"> earlier</a> post, I described how to install Twitter Bootstrap in your Rails project. Today, I was updating my <a href="http://www.derikstrattan.com/">portfolio</a> to use <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/"> CloudFront</a> as a content delivery service. After opening the page in Firefox, I noticed that the <a href="http://fontawesome.io/"> FontAwesome</a> icons were missing. This problem did NOT occur when the page was opened with Chrome or Safari. After more than 4 hours of troubleshooting, I had the page loading properly in Firefox. I sincerely hope that this post saves you countless hours and head scratching. Feel free to leave comments or suggestions. ^.^
</p>


<h1>FontAwesome</h1>

<p>
  When you download FontAwesome, you will notice that there are 4 different files. What are these? FontAwesome comes in multiple formats so the maximum number of users (read: browsers) can see your fonts:
  <ol>
    <li>Safari & Opera browsers = .toff & .otf</li>
    <li>IE9+, Firefox, Chrome = .woff</li>
    <li>iOS and Android = .svg</li>
    <li>IE8 and older = .eot</li>
  </ol>
</p>


<h1>HTTP Caching</h1>

<p>
  Before we dive head-first into setting up CloudFront, it's worth taking a slight detour to learn about HTTP caching and headers. According to <a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/increasing-application-performance-with-http-cache-headers"> Heroku</a>, "HTTP caching occurs when the browser stores local copies of web resources for faster retrieval the next time the resource is required. As your application serves resources it can attach cache headers to the response specifying the desired cache behavior." For our purposes, we need to understand <b>cache header</b>.
</p>


<p>
  Firefox and IE9+ reject all cross-site font requests unless some specific headers are set, i.e. ```Access-Control-Allow-Origin```. In other words, Firefox will not display a font if you use CloudFront to deliver content. For in-depth understanding, read more <a href="http://www.bryandragon.com/articles/rails-asset-pipeline-cdns-and-serving-cross-domain-fonts/">here</a> and <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/11261805/rails-3-font-face-failing-in-production-with-firefox">here</a>. We'll need to figure out a way to allow Firefox access to the fonts.
</p>


<h1>Configuring CloudFront</h1>

<p>
  <img src="https://www.llamaproducts.com/assets/product_pics/decal_meat_n_taters.gif"> <br> Ahhh, we have finally arrived at the meat and 'taters of this article. Let's set up CloudFront (if you have questions, refer to this <a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/using-amazon-cloudfront-cdn-with-rails#testing"><i>post</i></a> on Heroku. But first, what <b>IS</b> CloudFront? Many developers use Amazon S3 (simple storage service) to store static assets (e.g. images, javascript, CSS). It is also sometimes used to <b>serve</b> those assets, but this is not recommended because the S3 was not designed to serve files when your website is under heavy traffic. CloudFront is referred to as a Content Delivery Network (CDN), and acts to serve those assets that you stored on S3.
</p>


<h2>CloudFront setup</h2>

<p>
  <ol>
    <li>Make an <a href="http://aws.amazon.com">AWS account</a>.</li>
    <li>Login to your account, and go to <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home">CloudFront control panel</a>. Click 'Create distribution', and when prompted for the delivery method, select 'Web'. For now, use defaults. NOTE: If you wish to use CNAME, you must enter your domain under 'Origin Domain Name'. </li><br> <img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/heroku.devcenter/heroku_assets/images/224-original.jpg">
  </ol>
</p>


<h2>Configure CloudFront and Rails</h2>

<p><p>
  1) In your Rails application, go to <code>config/environments/production.rb</code>.<br>
  2) Look for the setting labelled <code>asset_host</code>. This setting is responsible for prepending a domain onto all asset links created via the built in asset helpers.<br>
  3) In your CloudFront Management Console, select the distribution that you created. Click the link &ldquo;Distribution Settings&rdquo;. Look for the subheader <b>Domain Name</b>, and copy that domain name. In your Rails app, paste in the domain: <code>config.action_controller.asset_host = "&lt; YOUR DISTRIBUTION SUBDOMAIN&gt;.cloudfront.net"</code>.
</p></p>

<h2>Purge content from CloudFront</h2>

<p>We need to create an invalidation in the <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home">CloudFront Panel</a>.To read more about why, go <a href="http://www.red-team-design.com/firefox-doesnt-allow-cross-domain-fonts-by-default">here</a> <br>
Let&rsquo;s find our fontawesome assets. In your terminal, go to: <code>~/project_name/public/assets</code> and type <code>ls -al fontawesome-webfont-*.*</code>. You should see something like this:
<code>ruby public/assets
fontawesome-webfont-4d228e1a1ddd570d6380dcd9b1a11d5c.ttf
fontawesome-webfont-6cfa562c51325bb1df40b64732dc8699.woff
fontawesome-webfont-9169b7b7c593388d41dd3c339df5b86b.svg
fontawesome-webfont-e742c0f297e307a74bdf4ca3c19073a2.eot
</code></p>

<p>Back in the CloudFront Panel, choose the tab <strong>Invalidations</strong>. Click <button>Create Invalidation</button>.
<br>
<img class="<a" src="href="http://user-image.logdown.io/user/1/blog/317/post/52439/eWU50lLhRqWSbj89efo7_invalid1.png">http://user-image.logdown.io/user/1/blog/317/post/52439/eWU50lLhRqWSbj89efo7_invalid1.png</a>" title="&ldquo;blog.xdite&rdquo;" >
<br>
Paste in the above assets like this:
<code>ruby
assets/fontawesome-webfont-4d228e1a1ddd570d6380dcd9b1a11d5c.ttf
assets/fontawesome-webfont-6cfa562c51325bb1df40b64732dc8699.woff
assets/fontawesome-webfont-9169b7b7c593388d41dd3c339df5b86b.svg
assets/fontawesome-webfont-e742c0f297e307a74bdf4ca3c19073a2.eot
</code>
<br>
<strong>IMPORTANT</strong> Don&rsquo;t forget to add <code>assets/</code> in front of the fontawesome.
<br>
Click <button>Invalidate</button>. Now wait for 5-10 minutes CDN cache to become invalidated.</p>

<h1>Install the CORS gem</h1>

<p>In your Gemfile:
<code>
gem 'rack-cors', :require =&gt; 'rack/cors'
</code>
Run <code>bundle</code>.
<br>
In your project folder, go to: <code>config/application.rb</code> and add the following:
<br>
``` ruby config/application.rb
module Portfolio
  class Application &lt; Rails::Application
  # &hellip;</p>

<pre><code>config.middleware.insert_before ActionDispatch::Static, Rack::Cors do
allow do
  origins '*'
  resource '*',
  headers: :any,
  methods: [:get, :options]
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
  #&hellip;</p>

<pre><code>config.assets.paths &lt;&lt; Rails.root.join("app", "assets")
config.assets.precompile += %w( .svg .eot .woff .ttf )
config.assets.header_rules = {
  :global =&gt; {'Cache-Control' =&gt; 'public, max-age=31536000'},
  :fonts  =&gt; {'Access-Control-Allow-Origin' =&gt; '*'}
}
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
<code>
&lt;br&gt;
The first part of this configuration puts the CORS gem at the top of your stack. Confirm this by running</code> rake middleware <code>in your terminal. Any header is now able to be retrieved via the</code> get <code>method. The second part precompiles the FontAwesome assets by specifically looking for their file extension. It also allows font control via the</code> header_rules ```.</p>

<h2><strong>Push to Heroku</strong></h2>

<p><p>
You are now ready to push everything up to Heroku. Don&rsquo;t forget to manually precompile assets, if necessary.
</p></p>

<h3>Additional Resources</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/rumblelabs/asset_sync">Rails, S3, and asset sync</a><br>
<a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/http-caching-ruby-rails">HTTP caching with Rails</a><br>
<a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/rack-cache-memcached-rails31">Rack::Cache</a></p>

<p><h3> What&rsquo;s next?</h3>
  In the next blog, I will explain how I moved this blog over from <a href="https://www.heroku.com/">Heroku</a> to <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub pages</a>. If this post helped you, feel free to leave a comment. Thanks and good luck coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Twitter Bootstrap]]></title>
    <link href="http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/11/03/installing-twitter-bootstrap/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-03T12:34:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://Derikulous.github.ioyear/11/03/installing-twitter-bootstrap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Mission: Install and use Twitter Bootstrap with Ruby on Rails</h1>

<h2><strong>Boss</strong>: Twitter Bootstrap</h2>

<p>I remember when I first started using <a href="http://getbootstrap.com/">Twitter Bootstrap</a> in early Sept 2013. I really had no idea what I was doing, and spent countless hours ineffectively using the CSS files. As a result, I found myself very frustrated and wondering why this plugin was any better than just creating CSS from scratch. While participating in Startup Weekend, a friend showed me what I was doing wrong and my whole approach to using Twitter Bootstrap changed. I dove into the documentation and found a number of inspiring CSS/Javascript effects. In an effort to help others learn from my mistakes, I&rsquo;ve created the following tutorial to get you started on basic installation and usage in your Ruby on Rails project.</p>

<h2><strong>Installation</strong></h2>

<p>Installing Twitter Bootstrap in your rails project is mostly as simple as requiring it in your gemfile. However, there are a few flavors that you can install, as well as two versions (2.3.2 or 3.0.1).</p>

<p>Variations include: <a href="https://github.com/anjlab/bootstrap-rails">Twitter Bootstrap Vanilla</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/seyhunak/twitter-bootstrap-rails">Twitter Bootstrap with LESS</a>, or
<a href="https://github.com/thomas-mcdonald/bootstrap-sass">Twitter Boostrap SASS</a>.</p>

<p>For this tutorial, we will install Bootstrap with SASS. In your gemfile, include the following:</p>

<p><code>ruby Gemfile https://github.com/thomas-mcdonald/bootstrap-sass Link
gem 'sass-rails', '&gt;= 3.2' # sass-rails needs to be higher than 3.2
gem 'bootstrap-sass', github: 'thomas-mcdonald/bootstrap-sass'
</code>
Now run <code>bundle install</code> in the command line. This will install version 3.0.1 of Twitter Bootstrap.</p>

<p>Open up your project, and within the folder <strong>assets/stylesheets/</strong>, rename <strong>application.css</strong> to <strong>application.css.scss</strong>. Now add <code>@import "bootstrap";</code> anywhere in the file.<br>
In <strong>assets/javascripts/</strong>, make sure the file looks <strong>EXACTLY</strong> like this:
<code>ruby application.js
//= require self
//= require bootstrap
//= require tree
</code> This will preload all the javascript functionality that is included with Twitter Bootstrap.</p>

<h2><strong>Modifying Bootstrap</strong></h2>

<p>Now that Twitter Bootstrap has been installed, we can customize the pages by calling in special classes provided by Bootstrap. What do I mean by <em>special classes</em>? This is where the <strong><a href="http://getbootstrap.com/css/">documentation</a></strong> becomes important. Here is where I must stress the importance of following the documentation examples, so that you can easily learn and manifest the Twitter Bootstrap functionality.</p>

<h3>Examples</h3>

<p>As of this post, I have been using Twitter Bootstrap for two months. In this short time, I have used the following functionality the most:<br>
<strong>Jumbotron<br></strong>
<strong>Grid System<br></strong>
<strong>Buttons<br></strong></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s run through a quick implementation of these key pieces of Twitter Bootstrap.</p>

<h3><strong><a href="http://getbootstrap.com/components/#jumbotron">Jumbotron</a></strong></h3>

<p>This component adds a container component with specific styling to your page, which calls attention to anything written in it. It can be implemented easily by calling a &ldquo;jumbotron&rdquo; on a div. It looks like this:
``` ruby custom.css.scss</p>

<div class="jumbotron">
  <h1>Hello, world!</h1>
  <p>...</p>
  <p><a class="btn btn-primary btn-lg" role="button">Learn more</a></p>
</div>


<p>```
That jumbotron class is all that you need to specify to add this special functionality in your stylesheet! You can also see that there&rsquo;s another class in this code <strong>&ldquo;btn btn-primary btn-lrg&rdquo;</strong>. I&rsquo;ll introduce this now.</p>

<h3><strong><a href="http://getbootstrap.com/css/#buttons">Buttons</a></strong></h3>

<p>This component, as you have probably guessed, adds great looking buttons into your CSS. Taking the above example, <code>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn btn-primary btn-lg" role="button"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</code>, this adds a button by calling &ldquo;btn&rdquo;, followed by the color of the button &ldquo;btn-primary&rdquo;, and lastly the size is specified with &ldquo;btn-lg&rdquo;. There are <strong>six</strong> button colors: &ldquo;btn-default&rdquo;, &ldquo;btn-primary&rdquo;, &ldquo;btn-success&rdquo;, &ldquo;btn-info&rdquo;, &ldquo;btn-warning&rdquo;, and &ldquo;btn-danger&rdquo;. There are also four sizes: <strong>Large</strong>:&ldquo;btn-lg&rdquo;, Default (doesn&rsquo;t require any specification), <strong>Small</strong>: &ldquo;btn-sm&rdquo;, and <strong>Extra Small</strong>: &ldquo;btn-xs&rdquo;.</p>

<h3><strong><a href="http://getbootstrap.com/css/#grid">Grid System</a></strong></h3>

<p>This is arguably the most important component of Twitter Bootstrap. This class specification uses a 12 grid system, with responsive scale, to add size and location to DIV classes. I suggest following the link and reading more about this class. The class is called by the following command:
``` ruby custom.css.scss</p>

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-1">This is a medium size, 1 grid column</div>
</div>


<p>```
The grid system comes in large, medium, small, and extra-small variations.</p>

<h2><strong>Templates</strong></h2>

<p>Thanks to Twitter Bootstrap&rsquo;s popularity amongst web developers and designers, a number of free and paid-for templates exist for Twitter Bootstrap v2.3.2 and v3.0. These are a few of my favorite sites: <br>
<strong>FREE:</strong><br>
<a href="http://bootswatch.com/">Bootswatch</a><br>
<a href="http://bootstrapstyler.com/">Bootstrapstyler</a><br>
<strong>PAID:</strong> <br>
<a href="ttps://wrapbootstrap.com/">Wrap Bootstrap</a><br>
In fact, it&rsquo;s easy to implement themes from <strong>Bootswatch</strong> by specifying in your <code>application.css.scss</code> file, <code>@import "bootstrap/Flatly"</code>. This will import the <strong><a href="http://bootswatch.com/flatly/">Flatly</a></strong> theme from Bootswatch in your project.<br>
I suggest diving deeper into all the benefits that Twitter Bootstrap provides. Try out <strong><a href="http://fontawesome.io/">Font-Awesome</a></strong> and <strong><a href="http://getbootstrap.com/components/#glyphicons">Glyphicons</a></strong></p>

<h2><strong>Links</strong></h2>

<p>If you like what you&rsquo;ve seen so far, try your hand at implementing templates by following <strong><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/derikulous/picasso-pirate">this</a></strong> tutorial I created.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
